Francisco d'Albertas Gomes de Carvalho

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER

International Institute for Sustainability (IIS). Estrada Dona Castorina, 124 Horto, Rio de Janeiro, Brasil 22460-320

☑ francisco.albertas@gmail.com | 希 franciscodalbertas.netlify.app | ② franciscodalbertas | चि franciscodalbertas | ♥ FdAlbertas

About me___

Biologist with a master's and a PhD in Ecology with 10 years of experience working with applied research focusing on understanding how the spatial pattern of human-modified landscapes affects biodiversity, ecosystem services provision and the Climate. My main interests are related to landscape planning, spatial analysis, and the interface between science, policy, and impact evaluation.

Skills

R - MARKDOWN - GIS - DATA ANALYSIS - ECOSYSTEM SERVICE MODELLING - ECOLOGICAL RESTORATION - WRITING AND COMMUNICATION - GOOGLE EARTH ENGINE - SPATIAL PRIORITIZATION

Languages _____

PORTUGUESE (NATIVE) - ENGLISH (FLUENT) - FRENCH (ADVANCED) - SPANISH (INTERMEDIATE)

Education

Universidade de São Paulo São Paulo

PHD IN ECOLOGY

2017-2022

Universidade de São Paulo

São Paulo. Brasil

MASTER IN ECOLOGY 2013-2015

Universidade de São Paulo São Paulo

BIOLOGICAL SCIENCES DEGREE 2006-2011

Professional experience _____

Jobs

International Institute for Sustainability-IIS Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER AND DATA SCIENTIST AT THE PROJECT TRADE, DEVELOPMENT AND THE ENVIRONMENT HUB

2022

Laboratório de Ecologia da Paisagem e Conservação-LEPaC(Departmento de Ecologia, Universidade de São Paulo)

RESEARCH TECHNICIAN - SAO PAULO RESEARCH FOUNDATION TRAINING FELLOWSHIP AS PART OF THE BIODIVERSITY AND

ECOSYSTEM SERVICE SCENARIOS NETWORK (SCENNET)

Instituto Socioambiental - ISA São Paulo, Brasil

JUNIOR ENVIRONMENTAL ANALYST (INTERNSHIP) - PROTECTED AREAS MONITORING PROGRAME

Mineral Engenharia e Ambiente São Paulo, Brasil

JUNIOR ENVIRONMENTAL ANALYST (INTERNSHIP) - OIL AND MINING ENVIRONMENTAL IMPACT EVALUATION

CONSULTANCY

Aquaflora providing services to Vale S.A.

CONSULTANCY - EVALUATING THE BASELINE CONDITION OF PRIORITY ECOSYSTEM SERVICES AT WATERSHEDS POTENTIALLY

THREATENED BY MINING OPERATION IN MINAS GERAIS ||STATE

World Wildlife Fund - WWF Brazil

CONSULTANCY - MONITORING DEFORESTATION AND FIRE WITHIN AMAZONIA AND CERRADO PROTECTED AREAS

2012

2011 20

2011-2012

São Paulo, Brasil

2015-2017

São Paulo, Brazil

2021

São Paulo, Brasil

Francisco d'Albertas Gomes de Carvalho · Curriculum Vitae

Instituto Socioambiental - ISA

CONSULTANCY - MAPPING THREATS TO FEDERAL AND STATE PROTECTED AREAS IN BRAZIL

Klabin s/a Papel e Celulose

CONSULTANCY - PLANNING ECOLOGICAL CORRIDORS BETWEEN INDIGENOUS LANDS

Paraná, Brasil

2017-2018

São Paulo, Brasil

Bloomberg Philanthropies e Global Road Safety

São Paulo, Brasil

CONSULTANCY - FLORISTIC INVENTORY OF URBAN AREAS IN SAO PAULO

TEACHING

Fundação Getulio Vargas Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

PROFESSOR - CO-ORGANIZATION WITH CARLOS ALBERTO SCARAMUZZA OF A SHORT TERM COURSE ENTITLED LANDSCAPE USE, FOR MASTER IN MANAGEMENT STUDENTS

2022

Research experience_

Conservation Science Group, University of Cambridge

VISITING RESEARCHER SUPERVISED BY ANDREW BALMFORD

Cambridge, United Kingdom

Publications

- d'Albertas, F., Ruggiero, P., Pinto, L. F. G., Sparovek, G., & Metzger, J. P. (2023). Agricultural certification as a complementary tool for environmental law compliance. Biological Conservation, 277, 109847. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biocon.2022.109847
- 2. González-Chaves, A. D., Carvalheiro, L. G., Piffer, P. R., d'Albertas, F., Giannini, T. C., Viana, B. F., & Metzger, J. P. (2023). Evidence of time-lag in the provision of ecosystem services by tropical regenerating forests to coffee yields. Environmental Research Letters, 18(2), 025002. https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/acb161
- Pashkevich, M. D., d'Albertas, F., Aryawan, A. A. K., Buchori, D., Caliman, J.-P., Chaves, A. D. G., Hidayat, P., Kreft, H., Naim, M., Razafimahatratra, A., Turner, E. C., Zemp, D. C., & Luke, S. H. (2022). Nine actions to successfully restore tropical agroecosystems. Trends in Ecology & Evolution. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tree.2022.07.007
- 4. d'Albertas, F., González-Chaves, A., Borges-Matos, C., Zago de Almeida Paciello, V., Maron, M., & Metzger, J. P. (2021). Private reserves suffer from the same location biases of public protected areas. Biological Conservation, 261, 109283. https://doi.org/10.1016/j. biocon.2021.109283
- 5. d'Albertas, F., Costa, K., Romitelli, I., Barbosa, J. M., Vieira, S. A., & Metzger, J. P. (2018). Lack of evidence of edge age and additive edge effects on carbon stocks in a tropical forest. Forest Ecology and Management, 407, 57-65. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foreco. 2017.09.042
- 6. Acosta, A. L., d'Albertas, F., Leite, M. de S., Saraiva, A. M., & Metzger, J. P. W. (2018). Gaps and limitations in the use of restoration scenarios: A review. Restoration Ecology, 26(6), 1108-1119. https://doi.org/10.1111/rec.12882
- Metzger, J. P., Esler, K., Krug, C., Arias, M., Tambosi, L., Crouzeilles, R., Acosta, A. L., Brancalion, P. H., D'Albertas, F., Duarte, G. T., Garcia, L. C., Grytnes, J.-A., Hagen, D., Jardim, A. V. F., Kamiyama, C., Latawiec, A. E., Rodrigues, R. R., Ruggiero, P. G., Sparovek, G., ... Joly, C. (2017). Best practice for the use of scenarios for restoration planning. Current Opinion in Environmental Sustainability, 29, 14–25. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cosust.2017.10.004